1, Rosen Building, DTVC, Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

□ (+966) 506138685 | ≥ kbmajeed1@gmail.com | ★kbmajeed.github.io | • kbmajeed | • kbmajeed

"Interested in intelligence and autonomy for different systems"

# Summary\_

I'm a Robotics enthusiast. From Unmanned vehicles to Robotic surgery, I have passion for every system that can sense, think, and act on its own. My experience ranges from Signals and Communications (B.Eng), Systems, Robotics and Control theory (M.Sc), and currently, a Machine learning specialization (2nd M.Sc). I've had the opportunity to work with Ultrasonic and EMAT technologies for Oil and Gas In-line inspection. Similarly, I have experience in the communcations industry and once helped develop software for a medical facility.

## **Education**

## Georgia Institute of Technology (GeorgiaTech)

Atlanta GA, USA

M.Sc in Computer Science

Aug. 2018 - Exp. Sept. 2020

• Specialization in Machine Learning, current CGPA: 4.0/4.0 King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals

### Dhahran, S.Arabia

M.Sc in Systems Engineering

Jan. 2015 - Jan. 2017

Specialization in Systems, Robotics, and Control, CGPA: 3.72/4.0

**Osun State University** 

Osun, Nigeria

B.Eng in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

Sept. 2009 - Mar. 2013

• Specialization in Signals and Communications, CGPA: 4.7/5.0

# Work Experience \_

**ROSEN** Dubai, UAE

SENSORS AND ALGORITHMS ENGINEER - ROSEN RESEARCH AND TECHNOLOGY CENTER

Jul. 2018 - PRESENT

- · Implemented Machine learning algorithms for Automatic detection of Pipeline features such as Bends, GirthWelds, Dents, Tees
- Worked on PIG tool Distance-Time Mapping using Kalman Filtering and a Dynamic Model.
- Prepared and Cleaned data from UT and EMAT Experiments
- Developed Algorithms for Detection of Coating Disbondment in pipelines
- Developed GUI for Intelligent Pipeline Cleaning Status
- Built Desktop Application for Library of the Research Center

**Alcatel-Lucent** Lagos, Nigeria

3G UMTS ENGINEER

Feb. 2011 - Aug. 2011

Aug. 2014 - Jan. 2015

Feb. 2014 - Jul. 2014

- Worked on the Integration of 3G Network all over Lagos state
- · Performed NodeB and RRH installations, commissioning, upgrades, fiber-optic swaps, and troubleshooting
- Coordinated team of riggers and technologists for BTS Site inspection, surveys, and hand-over
- Worked on more than 250 BTSs with prompt response to NMC/NOC alarms

**Osun State University** Osun, Nigeria

GRADUATE ASSISTANT

- Supported faculty research activities in the Communications group
- · Assisted in Proctoring, Grading, and Tutoring
- · Organized laboratory sessions

SYSTEMS ANALYST

**Abike Memorial Clinics** Kwara, Nigeria

• Installation of relevant hardware and software to support clinical work

- · Maintain and organize medical records efficiently
- Troubleshooting of PC systems
- Developed GUI for contrast enhancement of Ultrasound images

APRIL 29, 2019 KABIR MUHAMMAD ABDULMAJEED · RÉSUMÉ

# **Projects and Skills**

M.Sc. Thesis Kfupm, S.Arabia

AUTONOMOUS SENSOR DEPLOYMENT USING AN UNMANNED AERIAL VEHICLE

2016

• Designed a Framework for the Control of a Quadrotor to deploy a Geophone sensor for Oil and Gas exploration

B.Eng. Thesis Uniosun, Nigeria

DESIGN AND CONSTRUCTION OF A MOBILE PHONE JAMMER USING EXTRINSIC NOISE

2013

• Designed circuitry using environmental noise for jamming cellular communications in the GSM band.

**Projects** 

MORE DETAILS ON MY WEBPAGE

• Learning Algorithms for Tradings, Exposure Fusion, Seam-carving for Image resizing, SeaLion Classification using CNN, ADRC Controller for

Quadrotors, Dinosaur name generation using RNN, Image Panoramas, Induction Motor Controller using Lyapunov Backstepping

Computing Skills

LANGUAGES, SOFTWARE, PACKAGES

• Python, Matlab, Simulink, VREP, NumPy, OpenCV, Keras, Linux, Sklearn, SolidWorks, ROS

# **Honors & Awards**

## INTERNATIONAL & NATIONAL

| 2015 | KFUPM-DGS, King Fahd University Graduate Fellowship   | Dhahran, S.Arabia |
|------|---|-------------------|
| 2014 | <b>B.E.S.T</b> , Runner-Up National Budding Engineers and Scientists Award - Fed. Ministry of Education | Abuja, Nigeria    |
| 2013 | Pro-Chancellor's Award, Overall 2nd best Undergrad performance, Osun State University                   | Osun, Nigeria     |
| 2013 | Vice-Chancellor's Award, Overall best performance from the College of S.E.T, Osun State University      | Osun, Nigeria     |
| 2013 | <b>Departmental Award</b> , Best performance from the EE Department, Osun State University              | Osun, Nigeria     |
| 2013 | FELD Award, Runner-Up, National Undergraduates Competition  | Lagos, Nigeria    |

# Referees

Dr. Samir Al-Amer samirha@kfupm.edu.sa

ASSOCIATE PROF. SCE KING FAHD UNI. OF P&M

Prof. Alamu O.J.

alamuoj@uniosun.edu.ng

FORMER VC OSUN STATE UNI.

Dr. Lasisi H.

lashammed@yahoo.com

LECTURER EE, OSUN STATE UNI.

APRIL 29, 2019